Center for Interdisciplinary Studies Records UA207
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Center for Interdisciplinary Studies Records
1992 -- 2010
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Center for Interdisciplinary Studies
School of Arts and Sciences
UA207
12.13 Linear Feet 11 boxes
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into one series: Unprocessed accessions.
Custodial History
DCA received a transferred of 13 boxes from Andrea Carlino in the Center for Interdisciplinary Studies on 2010-05-17. Accession number 2010.082; Job Log number; and RSA number. At accession, these boxes were stabilized, a process that included removing materials from binders and hanging file folders, and condensing the number of boxes to 10. Two boxes were marked as specifically relating to the American Studies program; all other boxes were only marked as CIS general or misc. Boxes contained significant amounts of personally identifiable information and financial information and will need to be weeded carefully at processing. The recommendation is that when this material is process it be divided out into its component programs, at a minimum for the American Studies Program and the Latin American Studies program.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of audio and audiovisual materials, course materials, newspaper clippings, publications, reports, and student records related to the Center for Interdisciplinary Studies.
Biographical / Historical
The Center for Interdisciplinary Studies at Tufts University was established in June, 1992. Its purpose is to "bring together programs under one umbrella to increase the dialogue among the programs and spark joint endeavors, deepen our collective understanding of the nature, aims, and methods of interdisciplinary teaching, create new courses, new formats for experiential learning and new methods of faculty development, and generate various kinds of special programming, including lectures, workshops and symposia on interdisciplinary topics" (Bulletin, 1997-1998).
One early event was the Somerville Conversations. In 1995, The Center for Interdisciplinary Studies worked with the city of Somerville to unite Somerville residents, students, faculty, and staff from Tufts to participate in a dialogue about American identity and community.
The Center for Interdisciplinary Studies is located in Eaton Hall.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Academic Centers and Institutes; Curriculum and Instruction -- Teaching Material
- Additional accessions, UA207.000011
  - Center for Interdisciplinary Studies Records, 1992 -- 2010; UA207-001 (Box data_value_missing_f997e53b9fab217e873dad6a83971c1c, Box 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    20 years from date of creation.
  - Center for Interdisciplinary Studies Records, 1992 -- 2010; UA207-002 (Box data_value_missing_f997e53b9fab217e873dad6a83971c1c, Box 2)
  - Center for Interdisciplinary Studies Records, 1992 -- 2010; UA207-003 (Box data_value_missing_13969905491297612e3221778b0463b6, Box 3)
  - Center for Interdisciplinary Studies Records, 1992 -- 2010; UA207-004 (Box data_value_missing_13969905491297612e3221778b0463b6, Box 4)
  - Center for Interdisciplinary Studies Records, 1992 -- 2010; UA207-005 (Box data_value_missing_13969905491297612e3221778b0463b6, Box 5)
  - Center for Interdisciplinary Studies Records, 1992 -- 2010; UA207-006 (Box data_value_missing_520921a1c3e88d9b835d1f4d06a9ddc7, Box 6)
  - Center for Interdisciplinary Studies Records, 1992 -- 2010; UA207-007 (Box data_value_missing_520921a1c3e88d9b835d1f4d06a9ddc7, Box 7)
  - Center for Interdisciplinary Studies and American Studies records, 1992 -- 2010; UA207-008 (Box data_value_missing_520921a1c3e88d9b835d1f4d06a9ddc7, Box 8)
  - Center for Interdisciplinary Studies and American Studies records, 1992 -- 2010; UA207-009 (Box data_value_missing_f997e53b9fab217e873dad6a83971c1c, Box 9)
  - Oversized Center for Interdisciplinary Studies records, 1992 -- 2010; UA207-010 (Box data_value_missing_f997e53b9fab217e873dad6a83971c1c, Box 10)
  - CIS media, UA207-011 (Box data_value_missing_0742dd2c0330505dbcbccee19d6e5549, Box 11)
    Open for research.
    Scope and Contents
    Material accessioned with Women's Studies Program records (UA220) but actually part of Center for Interdisciplinary Studies.Not stabilized.